SENIOR RUBY DEVELOPER · FULL STACK

📕+7 (921) 368-01-95 | 🗷 job.dmm@qmail.com | 🖸 maxd | 🗟 maxim-dobryakov | 🛅 maxim-dobryakov | 🐧 closer.home | 🔮 mdobryakov

Summary_

I'm Ruby On Rails Software Developer with 15+ years of experience in backend and frontend development. My DevOps skills and experience with Kubernetes, AWS, Azure and Docker assist with investigation and fixing different problems as a result it save company's money.

Experience

Umbrellio (umbrellio.biz)

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER/TECH LEAD

Feb. 2021 - Present

- Improved development culture in my team (simplified code review process, accelerated CI and fixed blinking tests, motivated junior developers to grow up, etc.) as a result 95% of tasks took less than 21 days for development.
- · Coordinated development of important tasks between several departments and significantly improved communication between them.
- Redesigned several internal REST/GraphQL APIs as a result some reports became work 2 times faster.
- Investigated and fixed performance problems with SQL queries and Ruby applications.

Qoden (qoden.com)

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Sep. 2018 - Aug. 2020

- Successfully completed integration with several blockchains and payment systems which increased customers revenue to several times.
- · Recreated administration panel for a digital currency exchange and made it simple, clear and fast.
- · Redesigned and migrated some exchanges to cheap infrastructure (reduced the cost of own by 80-90%)
- Modernized several microservices and tools to improve and accelerate the development process.

SPB TV (spbtv.com)

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Jan. 2013 - Apr. 2018

- Created ETL platform for processing and storing incoming events from mobile apps and video streamers. It collected data and generated different kinds of reports about video watch sessions. At that time this system processed more than 10 000 events/sec and can be scaled up to 1M events/sec or even more.
- Together with team architected RESTful API server for SPB TV Rosing OTT/IPTV and Lebara Play OTT platforms.
- Supported with creation a new infrastructure use Puppet, Docker, Team City, and some AWS services (EC2, ELB, Route 53, S3, RDS, ElastiCache), focusing on high-availability, fault tolerance, and auto-scaling.

Studio Mobile (studiomobile.ru)

TEAM LEED

Jun. 2010 - Dec. 2012

- Designed and implemented REST API and admin panel for e-books mobile application with integrated shop for selling PDF, EPUB and interactive e-books.
- Produced CMS and API for the Special K mobile application. It provided information about the Special K products, kept a record of consumed calories calculated BML etc.
- Re-wrote Java server for embedded system to NIO and solved problems with packet loss, performance and integration with third-party systems.

Extracurricular Activity

Billfold (billfoldpos.com)

BILLFOLD (BACKEND DEVELOPER)

Aug. 2016 - Apr. 2018

Billfold is a platform to simplify and increase sales on different media events, cafe, bars, etc.

- · Led development of REST API for Billfold platform as a result it can handle hundreds devices without critical delays.
- Created deployment infrastructure in AWS and optimized it for high performance.

Keylord

PROTONAIL (CO-FOUNDER & SOFTWARE DEVELOPER)

2014 - 2020

Keylord is own shareware product created to simplify development of Redis and Memcached based applications. Last version of Keylord re-wrote to Kotlin, supports different key-value databases and works faster and better than OSS and commercial analogs.

Skills

Programming Languages Ruby, Java, Kotlin, C#, Go

Frameworks/Libraries Ruby on Rails, React, Sinatra, RSpec, Cucumber, Grape, dry-rb, etc.

Databases/Stores PostgreSQL, MySQL/MariaDB, HP Vertica, Redis, Memcached, RabbitMQ, Cassandra, MongoDB

DevOps skills Docker, Kubernetes, Ansible, Terraform, Puppet, AWS/Azure/DO/OVH, etc.

Services PayPal, Stripe, FastSpring, BrainTree, 2Checkout (now Verifone), Secure Trading (now Trust Payments), Twilio

Education

Saint Petersburg Electrotechnical University ETU "LETI" ENGINEER DEGREE OF MATHEMATICS

Faculty of Computing Technology and Informatics, specialization of Software of Computers and Computer System.